<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Tox Development blog]]></title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.tox.im/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-01T11:37:09.174Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.tox.im/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tox Foundation]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[support@tox.im]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Major Discovery by the Tox Foundation]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/tox-ftl/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/tox-ftl/</id>
    <published>2015-04-01T11:10:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-01T11:35:59.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Tox Foundation has made an important discovery today that might change the world forever.</p>
<a id="more"></a>

<p>Our research team at the Tox foundation has made an important discovery today. Data packets travel at the speed of light meaning finding a way to make them travel slightly faster is not that hard. The trick is to make the wire itself go fast in order to transmit the data inside at faster than light speeds. The following diagram should explain very well how it works.</p>
<img src="/images/Tox_ftl.png">

<p>Faster than light information travel allows us to send information back and forward in time by tweaking the packet parameters.</p>
<p>I managed to communicate with myself from the future and this is what I managed to understand. The connection was very flaky because of the dimensional noise created when someone interferes with his past. Here is the news from the future:</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/introducing-toxcoin" target="_blank" rel="external">Toxcoin</a> died a slow death after not a single developer was found that wanted to develop it.</p>
<p>qTox is doing very well competing with other web browsers.</p>
<p>uTox was rewritten in javascript and became a web client.</p>
<p>Toxic was acquired by Microsoft and ported to Windows, it will soon be replacing Skype.</p>
<p>Antox was slowly replaced by uTox for android.</p>
<p>nTox is still alive.</p>
<p>I also received this image but can’t make sense of it.</p>
<img src="/images/Tox_ftl_message.png">


<p>The connection was then cut suddenly. I will try to find out why the connection cut and why I can’t seem to be able to contact the future anymore.</p>
<p>Happy Future Toxing.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The Tox Foundation has made an important discovery today that might change the world forever.</p>
]]>
    
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Tox for Chrome OS preview]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/tox-chromeos/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/tox-chromeos/</id>
    <published>2015-04-01T05:10:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-01T09:06:43.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tox development preview for Chrome OS</p>
<a id="more"></a>

<p>With the advent of the Chromebook, the face of modern computing<br>changed in a number of drastic ways. Super low cost but fully<br>usable machines with browsers, chat programs, and full office<br>suites became available to even the lowest income students.</p>
<p>These devices let users shift from low budget bottom of the<br>barrel laptops often times filled to the brim in spyware and<br>adware to light and responsive machines boasting great battery<br>life and access to services they already use, something that<br>can only be looked at as a win for consumers.</p>
<p>With the announcement of even cheaper Chromebooks and sticks,<br>we realize the value in providing secure messaging with friends<br>and families to this ever expanding market more than ever.</p>
<p>As such, we’d like to announce the Tox for Chrome OS technical<br>preview. You’ll be one of the very first testers to this so<br>tons of bugs and issues are to be expected. While these clients<br>work, we do not encourage you to use them as your daily drivers.<br>You may experience data loss or other bugs that could prevent<br>you from using it correctly in some cases because of how early<br>this preview is.</p>
<h1 id="Getting_started">Getting started</h1>
<ul>
<li>To test Antox for Chrome OS please click <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/antox/mblkomdgjiaclkhabhmhnkmkfbbclgdi" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></li>
<li>To test uTox for Chrome OS please click <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/%CE%BCtox/cpbcplbgcffgmhagekhlifhpaihcgokf" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="Reporting_issues">Reporting issues</h1>
<ul>
<li>To report Antox issues please visit the issue tracker <a href="https://github.com/subliun/Antox/issues" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></li>
<li>To report uTox issues please visit the issue tracker <a href="https://github.com/notsecure/wintox/issues" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Tox development preview for Chrome OS</p>
]]>
    
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Tox, bringing your friends closer]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/tox-friends-2015/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/tox-friends-2015/</id>
    <published>2015-04-01T04:00:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-31T21:59:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While PC usage is on the decline, mobile usage has skyrocketed</p>
<a id="more"></a>

<p>and will continue to skyrocket in the future. We’ve come to realize<br>that because of this we need to start working to support mobile<br>and mobile device users as best we can.</p>
<p>With <a href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/introducing-toxcoin/" target="_blank" rel="external">ToxCOIN</a> support having been recently<br>announced we realized progress was being made in the right direction,<br>but it wasn’t enough. We realized that some people might still<br>want to use traditional Tox IDs and use mobile devices at the<br>same time so we decided to take a step back from what we’re used<br>to and look at what much of our mobile using audience is already doing.</p>
<p>We saw typical mobile users send short video clips, talk in groups,<br>message automatically without setup, but nothing would work for Tox.<br>That was, until we noticed someone send a cute little heart icon to<br>her friend to express a complex feeling.</p>
<p>We realized that if one little character could express a whole emotion,<br>a couple of them could express a Tox ID, and so emoji support was born.</p>
<p>Starting today, most of our clients now support fun and friendly emoji<br>in place of existing scary and frightening Tox IDs, be it uTox or Toxy<br>with more clients in the works.</p>
<p>Ready to try it out? lean back, open uTox Android, and punch in<br><code>🌔💡⭩⬃⚿🚧⟛⋏⩮🚍🛱💖🖭⚏⋻😇∁⤔ℐ⋜↷⚑⍕👫≧ℇ😇</code> to join our always<br>popular groupchat in style.</p>
<p>Want to make your own emoji ID? Checkout the tools <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/base_emoji" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>While PC usage is on the decline, mobile usage has skyrocketed</p>
]]>
    
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Introducing Toxcoin]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/introducing-toxcoin/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2015/04/01/introducing-toxcoin/</id>
    <published>2015-04-01T04:00:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-31T17:51:09.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new cryptocurrency to solve the issues tox has.</p>
<a id="more"></a>

<p>The main issues Tox face are that since we do not have central servers things<br>like making multiple devices have the same “account” and offline messaging is<br>very difficult. For this reason we have searched long and hard for a real<br>decentralized solution to these problems. We are proud to announce today that<br>we have found such a solution. This solution also has far reaching applications<br>and could also for example enable the creation of more efficient crypto<br>currencies and solve world hunger.</p>
<p>So how does it work? First we define proof of trust as the amount of trust that<br>can be proven a node has in a distributed peer to peer network. The trust a<br>node has in the system is defined as the inverse of the non trust a node has in<br>the system. Trusted nodes are assumed to always behave correctly meaning<br>untrusted nodes will not behave correctly. By making each node look for nodes<br>that do not behave correctly non trusted nodes can therefore be identified and<br>disposed of by the network. This leaves a network that only contains trusted<br>nodes. Once a network is certain to contain only trusted nodes any system which<br>requires such a system can easily be implemented on top meaning it is possible<br>to implement every centralized system in an efficient decentralized manner.</p>
<p>Creating a decentralized internet will therefore be possible. The possibilities<br>are endless. With this revolutionary new technology anybody will be capable of<br>having their own website.</p>
<p>Why name this technology toxcoin? The best way to get this technology up and<br>running fast and to fund development is to make it its own crypto currency.<br>Toxcoin will also be used to fund development of Tox. Tox developers will be<br>payed in Toxcoins which will increase in value as more and more people used<br>Tox. If we assume a total market cap of 1 million toxcoin and assume each tox<br>user is worth 10$. When Tox reaches 1 billion users each toxcoin will be worth<br>10000$. Toxcoins are clearly an investment that will only grow in value.<br>Investing in this con will truly increase your money.</p>
<p>Is this an altcoin? No, toxcoin will be implemented using the bitcoin<br>blockchain as a base.</p>
<p>There is already some proof of concept code in the github repo but it is still<br>in very early stages.</p>
<p>See the whitepaper: <a href="https://coin.tox.im/whitepaper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="external">coin.tox.im/whitepaper.pdf</a></p>
<p>Github repo: <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/toxcoin" target="_blank" rel="external">github.com/irungentoo/toxcoin</a></p>
<p>Join the revolution: <a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23toxcoin" target="_blank" rel="external">#toxcoin</a> on Freenode.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>A new cryptocurrency to solve the issues tox has.</p>
]]>
    
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[GSoC, languages, and more]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/03/18/gsoc-translations-more/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2015/03/18/gsoc-translations-more/</id>
    <published>2015-03-18T21:49:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-19T01:30:59.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Howdy folks, I feel like it’s a good time to get you all up to speed with Tox development.<br><a id="more"></a></p>
<h2 id="GSoC">GSoC</h2>
<p>For the 2nd year in a row, <a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/org2/google/gsoc2015/tox" target="_blank" rel="external">Tox got accepted in to GSoC</a>. This is great news and will both help new students learn about and start contributing to open source, and help Tox developers improve our projects and advance our goals of making security mainstream.</p>
<p>Want to contribute to Tox in GSoC but you’re not a C/C++ developer? Tox has plenty of projects like ToxMe improvements in Python, Tox for Windows in C#, iOS and Android clients in Java/Objective C that you might enjoy. You can checkout our full list of ideas <a href="http://wiki.tox.im/GSoC/2015/Ideas" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p>Ready to jump in and contribute to Tox? The deadline to write and submit a proposal for GSoC ends in a week but we encourage you to run it by us in <a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23tox-gsoc-students" target="_blank" rel="external">#tox-gsoc-students</a> for review so we can help you improve it.</p>
<h2 id="Translations">Translations</h2>
<p>Want to contribute to Tox and speak another language? Localization and being able to ensure Tox is accessible to as many people as possible is something we pride in, but not something we can do alone. Localization in Tox and our sites depends on our community and bilingual Toxers like you taking the time to submit and review translations, and is something we greatly appreciate.</p>
<p>If you want to spend a few minutes becoming a translator or reviewer for our new site signup <a href="https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/tox-website-next" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>, if you want we can also let you know of other things needing translations too.</p>
<h2 id="Toxcore">Toxcore</h2>
<p>The new API for toxcore mentioned in our last post is almost complete and almost ready to be merged, if you work on a client/wrapper/tool over Tox we encourage you to start porting your applications now. The new API is <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/toxcore/blob/new_api/toxcore/tox.h" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a></p>
<h2 id="Git_mirror">Git mirror</h2>
<p>We now maintain a Git mirror of popular Tox repositories for archive reasons, located at <a href="https://git.tox.im" target="_blank" rel="external">git.tox.im</a>. The mirror is powered by our fork of <a href="http://gogs.io" target="_blank" rel="external">Gogs</a> and can be used as a personal code host if you’d like. Being a personal/non Github host isn’t our main goal, but we don’t prohibit it and a couple users/contributors have started using it as such.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Howdy folks, I feel like it’s a good time to get you all up to speed with Tox development.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Update on the state of Tox]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2015/02/18/Update-on-the-state-of-Tox/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2015/02/18/Update-on-the-state-of-Tox/</id>
    <published>2015-02-18T18:49:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-23T20:57:39.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone. We realize it’s been a while since the last post, but a lot has happened and Tox continues to progress, so there’s a lot to talk about.<br><a id="more"></a></p>
<h2 id="Tox_core">Tox core</h2>
<h4 id="Core">Core</h4>
<p><a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/toxcore" target="_blank" rel="external">toxcore</a> has been largely in maintenance mode, with memory leaks, logic errors and other bugs being fixed every day. Recently work has begun on implementing a <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/toxcore/tree/new_api" target="_blank" rel="external">new, cleaner API</a> written by the <a href="https://github.com/sonOfRa/tox4j" target="_blank" rel="external">Tox4j</a> developers.</p>
<h4 id="Bootstrap_daemon">Bootstrap daemon</h4>
<p>As a small treat, the <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/toxcore/tree/master/other/bootstrap_daemon" target="_blank" rel="external">boostrap daemon</a> now has systemd support, thanks to contributor <a href="https://github.com/ray65536" target="_blank" rel="external">ray65536</a>. It is also available as the package <code>tox-bootstrapd</code> from our Linux repositories.</p>
<h4 id="New_groupchats">New groupchats</h4>
<p>Additionally, work is progressing on the complete <a href="https://github.com/JFreegman/toxcore" target="_blank" rel="external">groupchat re-design</a> and overhaul, started by <a href="https://github.com/alnf" target="_blank" rel="external">alnf</a> and currently being led primarily by <a href="https://github.com/JFreegman" target="_blank" rel="external">JFreegman</a>. Features include moderation abilities and group chat persistence (!). These group chats are a long way from being ready to merge into master; however, there is now a properly <a href="https://jenkins.libtoxcore.so/job/toxic_linux_beta/lastSuccessfulBuild/artifact/toxic" target="_blank" rel="external">modified build of Toxic</a> for Linux available with the changes.</p>
<p>You can also download the modified Toxic by installing <code>toxic-beta</code> from our Apt and Yum repos and running <code>toxic-beta</code>. Keep in mind that this copy is totally isolated from your existing Toxic install to prevent issues.</p>
<p>Please be aware that this is experimental testing code that will not work with the regular Tox network until we’ve finished it and merged it with master. You can follow development on the #tox-groupchats IRC channel on Freenode.</p>
<h1 id="Audio_filtering_and_echo_cancellation">Audio filtering and echo cancellation</h1>
<p>It’s been around for a few months now, but <a href="https://github.com/notsecure/uTox" target="_blank" rel="external">uTox</a> has had audio filtering, provided by <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/filter_audio" target="_blank" rel="external">code</a> from <a href="https://code.google.com/p/webrtc/" target="_blank" rel="external">WebRTC</a>. <a href="https://github.com/tux3/qTox" target="_blank" rel="external">qTox</a> now supports it as well.</p>
<h4 id="Experimental_echo_cancellation">Experimental echo cancellation</h4>
<p>Recently though, <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo" target="_blank" rel="external">irungentoo</a> (project founder and lead developer, in case you needed reminding :) ) has created <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/openal-soft-tox" target="_blank" rel="external">some patches for OpenAL</a> that allow for cancelling speaker echoes from your microphone’s sound input, a necessary feature for using a microphone without headphones or earbuds. uTox quickly put that to use, and qTox gained the same ability yesterday. Note that, if you compile these clients yourself, you will need to link against the patched version of OpenAL to enjoy echo cancellation. The official builds of both qTox and uTox are both built that way, and if you need to you can try using the <a href="https://jenkins.libtoxcore.so/search/?q=openal" target="_blank" rel="external">OpenAL builds</a> on <a href="https://jenkins.libtoxcore.so/" target="_blank" rel="external">Jenkins</a> used for qTox and uTox.</p>
<p>Currently echo cancellation is considered experimental, and Tox is seeking testing and feedback from users (on IRC or <a href="https://reddit.com/r/projecttox" target="_blank" rel="external">reddit</a>, for example) about how effective it is. If testing demonstrates that it is working properly, the patches will be submitted to the <a href="https://github.com/kcat/openal-soft" target="_blank" rel="external">OpenAL upstream</a> for merging.</p>
<h2 id="qTox_progress">qTox progress</h2>
<p>Besides continual minor improvements, qTox has gained the following major features.</p>
<h4 id="New_chatform">New chatform</h4>
<p>Over the last several months, <a href="https://github.com/krepa098" target="_blank" rel="external">krepa098</a> had been working on a complete rewrite of qTox’s chat form, and we’re happy to say that it was finally merged into master in the last week (over 4000 new lines of code!). Users should see significant reductions in memory and CPU usage (though some problems still exist), as well as being much prettier and easier to use. Copy and pasting in particular had been a big issue that should be pretty much solved, and there are some nice little animations (such as the typing notification).</p>
<h4 id="Local_file_encryption">Local file encryption</h4>
<p>Additionally, a fair bit of work (no where near as much as the new chat form required) was put into fixing the local file encryption and its interface in qTox, and that work was merged roughly two weeks ago. Users can now password protect their profile to safely transfer their profile to other computers, or even public computers. (Be sure to delete your profile when you leave a public computer!)</p>
<h4 id="Compact_contact_list">Compact contact list</h4>
<p>Finally, a lot of people probably love (or perhaps are unaware of) the new <a href="http://i.imgur.com/tmX8z9s.png" target="_blank" rel="external">compact contact list</a> option that qTox has, thanks to <a href="https://github.com/lumirayz" target="_blank" rel="external">lumirayz</a>.</p>
<h4 id="OS_X">OS X</h4>
<p>A note for Mac OS X users: We pushed a number of major changes that totally reworked how the app works. Because of this, many improvements like Qt 5.3 -&gt; 5.4 mean updating it normally will break. Please be aware that this update includes a new icon that you may not be used to, and has many visual improvements.</p>
<p>In order to update cleanly you’ll need to re-download qTox and drag the app in to your applications folder like usual. Your profiles won’t be harmed or modified in any way.</p>
<h2 id="uTox_progress">uTox progress</h2>
<p>uTox has been slowly receiving incremental improvements, primarily in the interface. For more details, you can check out the <a href="https://github.com/notsecure/uTox/commits/master" target="_blank" rel="external">commit log</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/irungentoo" target="_blank" rel="external">irungentoo’s Twitter</a>.</p>
<h2 id="Google_Summer_of_Code">Google Summer of Code</h2>
<p>Like last year, Tox is applying to be a participating organization in the Google Summer of Code. Check back soon for updates.</p>
<h2 id="Android">Android</h2>
<p>As mentioned above, work continues on Tox4j, the replacement Java wrapper for core, and when that’s complete a new Android client will be developed from scratch on top of it. Another vague possibility is that qTox can be ported to Android, since it’s written in Qt 5; <a href="https://github.com/tux3" target="_blank" rel="external">tux3</a> (qTox’s primary author) has recently started the very basic framework of such a port, but it is currently significantly less useful than the old Antox.</p>
<p>A fork of the old Antox is currently being maintained against the Tox4j work in progress. You can download it by joining the Google Play beta or adding our F-Droid repo. Details on this are <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="Website_improvements">Website improvements</h2>
<p>We’ve been continuously working to improve and refine the experience for new users by making things simpler and more straightforward. With this, we’re currently working on a new site for tox.im and a new downloads page until the site is complete.</p>
<p>You can check out progress on the new site <a href="https://beta.tox.im" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a> and check out the progress on the new temporary downloads page <a href="https://download.tox.im" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<h3 id="ToxMe_improvements">ToxMe improvements</h3>
<p>By popular demand we’ve added a reverse lookup API to ToxMe. This allows people to look up DNS Discovery names using just a Tox ID as long as the ID they want to lookup isn’t marked private. It is documented <a href="https://github.com/Tox/toxme.se/blob/master/api.md" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="Repository_improvements">Repository improvements</h2>
<p>If you use our RPM repo you may have suffered some issues downloading Tox due to an old revoked PGP key getting stuck in the signing process. We’ve gone ahead and fixed all the issues associated with that and ensured that it works perfectly.</p>
<p>Supporting our new downloads page, we’ve gone ahead and made the qTox packages automatically configure and setup the repo on your system by just installing the deb. This means for normal users all you’ll have to do is click download and Ubuntu software center will pop up to automatically set everything up and ensure you always have the latest and greatest copy of qTox. If you had the repo installed before it may cause conflicts in apt. Please remove it by running <code>rm /etc/apt/sources.list.d/toxrepo.list</code> and it’ll take care of itself automatically.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone. We realize it’s been a while since the last post, but a lot has happened and Tox continues to progress, so there’s a lot to talk about.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Tox Bootstrap Now Packaging for armhf]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/30/tox-bootstrap-now-packaging-for-armhf/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/30/tox-bootstrap-now-packaging-for-armhf/</id>
    <published>2014-12-01T02:08:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those who own a Raspberry Pi just sitting there, collecting dust after an impulse buying spree, you finally have a reason to use it.<a id="more"></a> With effort from our packager, Urras, we now have the tox-bootstrapd package available for anyone using an armhf instruction set, and quite possibly armel as well. Simply install the <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries#Apt.2FAptitude_.28Debian.2C_Ubuntu.2C_Mint.2C_etc..29" target="_blank" rel="external">Tox Repo</a> to your Apt or Yum-based distro and off to the races with ye’.</p>
<p>For more imformation as to what the Tox Bootstrap package does, and why Tox Nodes are important, visit our Running a Bootstrap Node page.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>For those who own a Raspberry Pi just sitting there, collecting dust after an impulse buying spree, you finally have a reason to use it.]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Tox Core" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Core/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Core/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Tox, packaging, and versions]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/23/tox-packaging-and-versions/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/23/tox-packaging-and-versions/</id>
    <published>2014-11-24T02:10:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-25T01:19:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As many of you know, Tox follows a pretty fun rolling release style alpha development cycle where a lot of code changes and improves very rapidly without any set pace.<br><a id="more"></a><br>Because of the oh so fast pace of this we spent a good deal of time designing a cross-OS compilation system that churns out the latest copy of Tox no more than 5 minutes after a commit was pushed ready to be tested by you, our lovely users.</p>
<p>Because we churned out builds so fast we knew we needed a way to make sure you always ran the latest version of Tox + your favourite client so you could enjoy all the new features and bug fixes as soon as is possible. As such we statically linked and packaged the Linux clients sitting in a repo we run, designed autoupdaters for our Windows clients, and spent a good deal working on efficient ways to update on OS X seamlessly.</p>
<p>While this system works out wonderfully for those users who pull the tox clients from this repo or use our autoupdaters, there still exists the group of users who use distribution created packages. The problem with distro packaging is that for rolling release software it reduces and slows our ability to get the latest features or security fixes directly in to your hands.</p>
<p>Our issue with distro packaging at this stage is simple, we don’t want our users to miss out on features or critical security fixes at the hand of slower packagers or the bureaucratic cycle/freeze model that some Linux distributions implement(looking at you, Debian).</p>
<p>Why is this post happening now of all times? Lemmie tell you a little story.</p>
<p>A few days back a user entered our IRC channel asking for help joining group chats, he explained that he just ran apt-get update/upgrade and installed the latest Tox package and he wasn’t getting invites to the chat at all. After a bit of questioning I realised he used an obscure Ubuntu fork aimed at older systems that shipped a copy of utox that was almost a month old. It turns out he was attempting to join the new audio group chats with a super old client. After he added our up to date and current repositories he had no more issues.</p>
<p>If you don’t think this mess is still an issue, <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/toxcore/compare/master%40%7B30day%7D...master" target="_blank" rel="external">I encourage you to take a look at all the changes that have happened to toxcore alone.</a></p>
<p>About versioning, it won’t happen while we’re in our rolling release alpha build cycle.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Happy Toxing, Sean</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>As many of you know, Tox follows a pretty fun rolling release style alpha development cycle where a lot of code changes and improves very rapidly without any set pace.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Tox Core" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Core/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Core/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[uTox now has Audio Filtering (Noise cancellation, etc..).]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/23/utox-now-has-audio-filtering-noise-cancellation-etc/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/23/utox-now-has-audio-filtering-noise-cancellation-etc/</id>
    <published>2014-11-24T00:06:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:26:28.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To turn it on, the dropdown is right beside the audio input settings in uTox. You can preview your filtered (or not) audio by clicking on the preview button.</p>
<p>Currently noise reduction and gain control are properly implemented.<br><a id="more"></a><br>This is what it uses to filter the audio: <a href="https://github.com/irungentoo/filter_audio" title="filter_audio" target="_blank" rel="external">github repo here</a> I put it in its own repo so other clients can easily add it too.</p>
<p>I really would like to know how well it performs so please try it out and tell us.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>To turn it on, the dropdown is right beside the audio input settings in uTox. You can preview your filtered (or not) audio by clicking on the preview button.</p>
<p>Currently noise reduction and gain control are properly implemented.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="μTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/%CE%BCTox/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Achievement Get: Groupchat Audio]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/15/achievement-get-groupchat-audio/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/11/15/achievement-get-groupchat-audio/</id>
    <published>2014-11-15T17:18:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’ve been promising it since our inception, and by God that time has finally come. With recent Toxcore commits, alongside implementation in our two leading clients, qTox and uTox, Tox users can now join groupchats and start audio calls.<br><a id="more"></a><br>If you’re currently running either qTox or uTox, we heavily suggest upgrading to the newest versions, as we’ve made great strides recently to implement one of the most requested features of Tox.</p>
<img src="/images/vsrykl.png">

<p>Here’s an audio sample of a music clip being played over group audio:</p>
<iframe width="100%" height="160" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fsoundcloud.com%2Fplebtier%2Ftox-group-audio&auto_play=false&hide_related=true&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&color=ff5500&show_artwork=true"></iframe>

<p>Song: <a href="http://cathndadrecords.bandcamp.com/track/london" target="_blank" rel="external">London by Satan &amp; Megastar</a> Licensed CC-BY 3.0</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>We’ve been promising it since our inception, and by God that time has finally come. With recent Toxcore commits, alongside implementation in our two leading clients, qTox and uTox, Tox users can now join groupchats and start audio calls.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="qTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Core" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/Tox-Core/"/>
    
      <category term="μTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/Tox-Core/%CE%BCTox/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Lets Tox, everywhere!]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/22/tox-on-your-wii/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/22/tox-on-your-wii/</id>
    <published>2014-10-22T20:56:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-25T01:19:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Howdy folks for the 2nd time today!</p>
<p>Remember that time you got Linux running on your Wii? When you managed to install Debian to your Raspberry Pi?</p>
<p>Wouldn’t it be <em>super cool</em> if you could Tox your friends without dealing with a compiler or git?<br><a id="more"></a><br>Thankfully we agree, and we know you have tons of other cases where x86/x86_64 might not be the architecture of your PC. We believe you should be able to Tox no matter where you are or what you use without a bunch of work or hacks, so we’re introducing the Tox Everywhere initiative.</p>
<p>Be it your PowerPC Mac running Linux or your Wii, the Tox Everywhere initiative was created to give everyone with whatever odd case you may have the same ease of ability to use Tox as our traditional x86 friends</p>
<p>In the coming weeks expect to see more posts on more architectures and clients, all ready to go directly in our repo so you can install Tox with the same repo instructions we already have on our <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries" title="binaries" target="_blank" rel="external">binaries</a> page.</p>
<p>Phase one of this program is targeting the Arm, Armv7, PowerPC, and PowerPC64 architectures and is currently being created as we speak. <a href="http://jenkins.libtoxcore.so/job/qTox-Linux-pkg/" title="PowerPC packages for qTox" target="_blank" rel="external">PowerPC packages for qTox</a> already exist ready for you to install, though they are not yet in the repo.</p>
<p>For the 2nd time, happy Toxing</p>
<p>ps: If you have any questions on what we’ll support or when shoot me an email or Tox me, sean [at] tox [.] im</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Howdy folks for the 2nd time today!</p>
<p>Remember that time you got Linux running on your Wii? When you managed to install Debian to your Raspberry Pi?</p>
<p>Wouldn’t it be <em>super cool</em> if you could Tox your friends without dealing with a compiler or git?<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Jenkins" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Jenkins/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Core" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Jenkins/Tox-Core/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Foundation" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Jenkins/Tox-Core/Tox-Foundation/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Jenkins/Tox-Core/Tox-Foundation/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Tox on OSX]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/22/tox-on-osx/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/22/tox-on-osx/</id>
    <published>2014-10-22T20:36:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-25T01:19:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hodwy folks,</p>
<p>After 27 whole days of delay our Tox downloads for OS X work again, and are better than ever!</p>
<p>We ran them previously, but progress on clients stagnated and we couldn’t justify the extra cost to build binaries that didn’t really work.<br><a id="more"></a><br>Now that qTox works great on OS X we’ve continued our builds for all our OS X users, you can download them <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries#OS_X" title="here" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p>Happy Toxing!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Hodwy folks,</p>
<p>After 27 whole days of delay our Tox downloads for OS X work again, and are better than ever!</p>
<p>We ran them previously, but progress on clients stagnated and we couldn’t justify the extra cost to build binaries that didn’t really work.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="qTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Core" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/Tox-Core/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[qTox now in Tox Repositories]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/20/qtox-now-in-tox-repositories/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/20/qtox-now-in-tox-repositories/</id>
    <published>2014-10-20T20:37:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took awhile, and some may have noticed it was there earlier, but qTox has now hit the Tox Repos. It’s a great addition to the already expansive list of Tox clients users have to choose from, and personally, I think it’s one of the best clients we have to offer.</p>
<p><a id="more"></a><br>If you haven’t already, <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries#Linux" target="_blank" rel="external">here are the instructions</a> on how to add the Tox Repo to your packaging software.</p>
<img src="/images/qtox-settings-window.png">
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>It took awhile, and some may have noticed it was there earlier, but qTox has now hit the Tox Repos. It’s a great addition to the already expansive list of Tox clients users have to choose from, and personally, I think it’s one of the best clients we have to offer.</p>
<p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="qTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/qTox/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Help Tox Grow, Run a Tox Node Today]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/06/help-tox-grow-run-a-tox-node-today/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/06/help-tox-grow-run-a-tox-node-today/</id>
    <published>2014-10-06T22:04:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In light of packaging the bootstrap daemon, we’re going to be running a month-long campaign to expand our current node list. For more information, visit our <a href="https://blog.libtoxcore.so/running-a-bootstrap-node" title="Running a Bootstrap Node" target="_blank" rel="external">Running a Bootstrap Node</a> page or join us on IRC #tox@freenode.<br><a id="more"></a><br>(Page will be fixed soon)</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>In light of packaging the bootstrap daemon, we’re going to be running a month-long campaign to expand our current node list. For more information, visit our <a href="https://blog.libtoxcore.so/running-a-bootstrap-node" title="Running a Bootstrap Node" target="_blank" rel="external">Running a Bootstrap Node</a> page or join us on IRC #tox@freenode.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Tox Core" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Core/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Toxic added to Tox Repositories]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/06/toxic-added-to-tox-repositories/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/06/toxic-added-to-tox-repositories/</id>
    <published>2014-10-06T07:35:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of our oldest, but feature-rich clients, <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Toxic" target="_blank" rel="external">Toxic</a>, has been added to the Tox Repos. Toxic uses an ncurses interface, and is written in C. All Unix-like operating systems are currently supported (e.g. Linux, OSX, FreeBSD).</p>
<p><a id="more"></a><br>If you haven’t added our repository yet, you can follow <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries#Repositories" target="_blank" rel="external">these instructions.</a> You can also download the packages directly <a href="https://jenkins.libtoxcore.so/job/toxic-linux-pkg/" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<img src="/images/toxic-0-5-1.png">
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>One of our oldest, but feature-rich clients, <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Toxic" target="_blank" rel="external">Toxic</a>, has been added to the Tox Repos. Toxic uses an ncurses interface, and is written in C. All Unix-like operating systems are currently supported (e.g. Linux, OSX, FreeBSD).</p>
<p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
      <category term="Toxic" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Repositories/Toxic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Ratox in Tox Repositories]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/04/ratox-in-tox-repositories/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/04/ratox-in-tox-repositories/</id>
    <published>2014-10-05T01:13:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Man, we’re on fire lately. Ratox, a relatively new client created by the wonderful people at <a href="www.2f30.org">2f30</a>, can now be found in Tox Repos. Unlike other clients relying on GUIs as an interface to the user, Ratox is developed with the UNIX-philosophy in mind and allows complete interaction through named pipes. For more info, visit the <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Ratox" target="_blank" rel="external">Ratox article</a> on the Tox Wiki.<br><a id="more"></a><br>If you’re new to Tox, or haven’t added our Tox Repository yet, check out <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries#Repositories" target="_blank" rel="external">the instructions</a> on how to add the Tox Repo to your software management suite.</p>
<img src="/images/ratox_small.png">
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Man, we’re on fire lately. Ratox, a relatively new client created by the wonderful people at <a href="www.2f30.org">2f30</a>, can now be found in Tox Repos. Unlike other clients relying on GUIs as an interface to the user, Ratox is developed with the UNIX-philosophy in mind and allows complete interaction through named pipes. For more info, visit the <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Ratox" target="_blank" rel="external">Ratox article</a> on the Tox Wiki.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Ratox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Ratox/"/>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Ratox/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Antox Release 0.14.0-alpha]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/03/antox-release-0-14-0-alpha/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/03/antox-release-0-14-0-alpha/</id>
    <published>2014-10-03T21:52:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-25T01:19:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It didn’t take long for another release to happen but here it is, version 0.14.0. This release mostly brings a lot of changes to under the hood. Namely, the entire code base has been moved from Java to Scala and with it came a new sleek UI with improved animations<br><a id="more"></a></p>
<img src="/images/antox-0-14-0.png">

<p>Hopefully this transition of language goes smoothly and everything works as well as it did before. Next in the development line is adding avatars and finally finishing off implementing audio calling</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>It didn’t take long for another release to happen but here it is, version 0.14.0. This release mostly brings a lot of changes to under the hood. Namely, the entire code base has been moved from Java to Scala and with it came a new sleek UI with improved animations<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Antox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Antox/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Toxic release v.0.5.2 (and groupchat issues)]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/03/toxic-release-v-0-5-2-and-groupchat-issues/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/03/toxic-release-v-0-5-2-and-groupchat-issues/</id>
    <published>2014-10-03T05:49:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-25T01:19:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Major changes include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ability to set an avatar. You can set it in the config file (see the <a href="https://github.com/Tox/toxic/blob/master/misc/toxic.conf.example" target="_blank" rel="external">example config file</a>) or with the command ‘/avatar &lt;path&gt;’ (Note: This command will only set it temporarily until you restart your client).</li>
<li>Previous chat history is now loaded when you open a chat window.</li>
<li>Chat log files are now renamed when a contact changes their name instead of creating a new log file and leaving the old one.</li>
<li>Resolved a performance issue where idle CPU usage was unacceptably high when compiled with sound notifications.</li>
<li>Some small UI changes that need no explanation.</li>
<li>Lots of important bug fixes<br>The currently ongoing toxcore groupchat rewrite broke Toxic’s implementation of groupchats. Any version of Toxic older than <strong>c56c6cc2</strong> will behave very strangely with the new groupchats (this may be temporary).</li>
</ul>
<p>Also, as of writing this GroupBot is up to date with the latest core, so if you can’t get an invite from him then you need to update your toxcore.</p>
<p>tldr; update everything</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Major changes include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ability to set an avatar. You can set it in the config file (see the <a href="https://github.com/Tox/]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Toxic" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Toxic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[uTox updates 0.1.a]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/02/utox-updates-0-1-a/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/10/02/utox-updates-0-1-a/</id>
    <published>2014-10-02T22:58:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:26:28.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The major update this week is the new groupchats that should work much better (connection wise) than the old ones. Note that as of now they are still missing important features like usernames but the base of them (joining/quitting/sending messages) should already work well.</p>
<p>As for uTox, mainly bug/translation fixes.</p>
<p>Also, I will be pushing updates in a more regular manner until group chats work well.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The major update this week is the new groupchats that should work much better (connection wise) than the old ones. Note that as of now th]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="μTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/%CE%BCTox/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[uTox now in Apt & Yum Repos]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.tox.im/2014/09/28/utox-now-in-apt-yum-repos/"/>
    <id>https://blog.tox.im/2014/09/28/utox-now-in-apt-yum-repos/</id>
    <published>2014-09-28T21:56:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-06T23:28:20.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>uTox is now the second Tox client to be hosted on the Tox Repositories, second to Venom.<br>If you haven’t already, add our Tox repo to Apt or Yum by following <a href="https://wiki.tox.im/Binaries#Repositories" target="_blank" rel="external">these instructions.</a> It’s a great way to get the latest changes to Tox clients in a quick and easy fashion.</p>
<p>32 and 64bit instructions supported; more to come in the upcoming week! (We’re in the process of getting Toxic and qTox on the repo as well!)</p>
<img src="/images/utox-small.png">]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>uTox is now the second Tox client to be hosted on the Tox Repositories, second to Venom.<br>If you haven’t already, add our Tox repo to A]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Tox Repositories" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Repositories/"/>
    
      <category term="μTox" scheme="https://blog.tox.im/categories/Tox-Repositories/%CE%BCTox/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
